RG 004:122, Salisbury Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Salisbury Probate Court records
1847-1962
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Salisbury District)
27.75 cubic feet
Record books, 1847-1962; Probate files, 1847-1919.
RG004_122
2000-003 and 2011-039
Historical Note
Salisbury, Litchfield County, Town established in October 1741
The Salisbury Probate District was constituted June 6, 1847, from the Sharon Probate District. The Salisbury Probate District merged with the Canaan, Cornwall, Norfolk, and Sharon Probate Districts on January 1, 2007 to create the Northwest Corner Probate District. The Northwest Corner Probate District merged with the Harwinton, Litchfield, and Thomaston Probate Districts on January 5, 2011, to create the Litchfield Hills Probate District. The Litchfield Hills Probate District serves the municipalities of Canaan, Cornwall, Harwinton, Kent, Litchfield, Morris, Norfolk, North Canaan, Salisbury, Sharon, Thomaston, and Warren.
Town of Salisbury, Probate District chronology:
October 1741 - October 1742, New Haven District
October 1742 - October 1755, Litchfield District
October 1755 - June 5, 1847, Sharon District
June 6, 1847 - December 31, 2006, Salisbury District
January 1, 2007 - January 4, 2011, Northwest Corner District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Litchfield Hills District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volume 1-40, 1847-1962. Volume 8 was missing from the probate court and not transferred to the Connecticut State Library. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 40. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1847-1919. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-039 are numbered 1 to 7, 9 to 40.
Probate files in accession 2000-003 are arranged in two sequences, the first covering 1847-1900 and the second covering 1900-1919. Files are alphabetical within each sequence.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2000-003.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Salisbury
Places:
Salisbury (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-039, Record books, 1847-1962, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1, 2, 4, 5, 9, 10, 11, 12, 14, 15, 17, 18, and 20, 1847-1917, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the. Volumes 3, 6-7, 13, 16, 19 were not filmed. Volume 8 is missing.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 2000-003 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on August 27, 1999.
The record books in accession 2011-039 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 28, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1847-1962; 19.5 cubic feet (39 volumes); 2011-039
  Volume 8 was missing from the probate court and not transferred to the Connecticut State Library
  - Records, 1847-1856 (Volume 1)
    Includes separate volume, "Distribution of the estate of John E. Coffing returned 2d March 1848..."
  - Records, 1856-1865 (Volume 2)
  - Orders and decrees, 1864-1878 (Volume 3)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1865-1875 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1875-1883 (Volume 5)
  - Orders and decrees, 1878-1885 (Volume 6)
  - Bonds, 1881-1926 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1883-1888 (Volume 9)
  - Orders and decrees, 1885-1895 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1888-1892 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1892-1898 (Volume 12)
  - Orders and decrees, 1895-1904 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1898-1902 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1902-1907 (Volume 15)
  - Orders and decrees, 1904-1912 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1907-1911 (Volume 17)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Records, 1911-1914 (Volume 18)
  - Orders and decrees, 1912-1920 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1914-1917 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1917-1921 (Volume 21)
  - Orders and decrees, 1920-1926 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1921-1924 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1924-1926 (Volume 24)
  - Orders and decrees, 1926-1933 (Volume 25)
  - Bonds, 1926-1962 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1926-1928 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1928-1930 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1930-1932 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1932-1934 (Volume 30)
  - Orders and decrees, 1933-1940 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1934-1935 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1935-1937 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1937-1939 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1939-1940 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1940-1941 (Volume 36)
  - Orders and decrees, 1940-1946 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1940-1942 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1942-1944 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1944-1945 (Volume 40)
- Probate files, 1847-1919; 8.25 cubic feet; 2000-003
  - 1847-1900
    - Acme - Clark (Box 1)
    - Cleaveland - Hydron (Box 2)
    - Jacobi - Pettee (Box 3)
    - Phelan - Swift (Box 4)
    - Tanner - Yerrington (Box 5)
  - 1900-1919
    - Adam - Funk (Box 6)
    - Gale - Pulver (Box 7)
    - Randall - Woodworth (Box 8)
  - Index (Box 9)